<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Random Forest on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/random-forest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Random Forest on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/random-forest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Showdown:  Random Forest vs Regression on EPA MPG Dataset</title>
      <link>/post/showdown/showdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/showdown/showdown/</guid>
      <description>Objective:I’m always curious about which model performs the best on data frames. Today I’m going to use the mpg dataset, which contains a subset of the fuel economy data the EPA makes available on http://fueleconomy.gov.
I am going to use city miles per gallon as the response variable and the rest of the variables as predictors, or dependent variables.
Split Data into Train and Test SetsI will use a 75%/25% Train/Test Split.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushroom Model</title>
      <link>/post/mushroom/mushrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mushroom/mushrooms/</guid>
      <description>Another FFTrees PostThis is great. Have you ever been on a walk in a creek and came across some mushrooms? And you think to yourself, “Man those look good? Perhaps I should bring those home?” Ok maybe not.
Well this blog is about building an FFtrees model developed by Nathaniel Phillips. The dataset consists of 8,124 mushrooms that are classified as Poisonous or Non Poisonous. Additionally there are 22 different variables identifying the mushroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Wine Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/red_wine/wine_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/red_wine/wine_report/</guid>
      <description>Objective: My objective was to see if I could predict whether a wine was good or bad using the Random Forest Algorithm (using Random Forest and FFTrees). To run the model I train it on 70% of the data. I then test it against the test set or the other 30% to see how it does. Before I start the random Forest I do some Exploratory Analysis to see those factors that contribute to a wine being classified a Good Wine.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>