<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Fun Data Analytics Blog on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Fun Data Analytics Blog on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The ROC Curve - Is it a mine or a rock? - Pick your Sensitivity</title>
      <link>/post/roc/roc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/roc/roc/</guid>
      <description>The Famous ROC CurveROC stands for Receiver Operating Characteristic. Its origin is from sonar back in the 40’s, where it was used to identify submarines – it likely helped save some schools of fish too as they could be misclassified as submarines and torpedoed. The ROC curve was an important metric in WWII and continues to be today.
Today the ROC curve is used in predictive modelling to distinguish between true positives and true negatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Showdown:  Random Forest vs Regression on EPA MPG Dataset</title>
      <link>/post/showdown/showdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/showdown/showdown/</guid>
      <description>Objective:I’m always curious about which model performs the best on data frames. Today I’m going to use the mpg dataset, which contains a subset of the fuel economy data the EPA makes available on http://fueleconomy.gov.
I am going to use city miles per gallon as the response variable and the rest of the variables as predictors, or dependent variables. I am also going to use the RMSE measure to compare the models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushroom Model</title>
      <link>/post/mushroom/mushrooms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mushroom/mushrooms/</guid>
      <description>Another FFTrees PostThis is great. Have you ever been on a walk in a creek and came across some mushrooms? And you think to yourself, “Man those look good? Perhaps I should bring those home?” Ok maybe not.
Well this blog is about building an FFtrees model developed by Nathaniel Phillips. The dataset consists of 8,124 mushrooms that are classified as Poisonous or Non Poisonous. Additionally there are 22 different variables identifying the mushroom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can the k means algorithm correctly identify a flower by its petal length and width alone?</title>
      <link>/post/kmeans/kmeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kmeans/kmeans/</guid>
      <description>K Means ClusteringK Means Clustering is awesome. It’s what’s called unsupervised learning where there is no prediction variable. The algorithm attemps to cluster data based on its similarity. So in this case I’m going to feed the algorithm the petal width and petal length of three sets of flowers and see whether or not can appropriately group the data.
To implement k means we have to specify the number of clusters we want the data to be grouped into.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many sunny days are followed by cloudy days in Seattle on any given year?</title>
      <link>/post/weather_post/mkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/weather_post/mkdown/</guid>
      <description>Seattle Sunny Day StreaksObjective: If you’re like me when the sun comes out after a couple cloudy days my mood lifts quite a bit - even more so than when it’s been sunny for a couple days. Perhaps its the contrast between the two? Nevertheless I was curious how many shifts on average we will have from cloudy days to sunny days, in other words how many mood lifts can we estimate to have in a year living in Seattle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial on Web Scraping (Basic) - Wiki Tables</title>
      <link>/post/website/rvest_tables_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website/rvest_tables_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Web Scraping Tutorial (Wiki Tables)One of my favorite things to do is to scrape web data for analysis in R. Below you will find a simple example where we will scrape a list of Messier Objects from Wiki.
Workflow for Scraping Wiki TablesRead in page needed to scrape;Scrape the Table using Rvest (Wiki Tables do not need the Node function);Convert to Data Frame;Clean up Data;Analyze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Regex or to Not?</title>
      <link>/post/regex/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/regex/untitled/</guid>
      <description>Is Regex Necessary?Yep. If you’re new to programming or R. Learn Regex. It will help you so much when your data asks of you to do data-gymnastics. Below you will find the steps I took to start learning Regex.
Online Tutorialhttp://www.regexone.com
This is a great site to get your feet wet. You can do it in an hour and when you’re done you’ll have a working knowledge of Regex and be able to do the most common Regex tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer is Leaving Town</title>
      <link>/post/summer_leaving/summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/summer_leaving/summer/</guid>
      <description>I’ve never been good with saying good-bye. But that’s exactly what I find myself doing. Waving good bye to Summer and its caravans of warm sunny days, clear lakes and long evenings trail behind. And even if the curtain comes back up in September and Summer plays a finale – I know – the show – is coming to an end. It just sucks!
Over the past few months I have had the best time – from my first overnight hike (in the dark) at Ancient Lakes to climbing 4,000 ft with my Niece at Crystal Mountain inside Mount Rainier National Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Melt and Cast When You Can Recast?</title>
      <link>/post/melt/melt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/melt/melt/</guid>
      <description>Reshape Data Practice (Melt/Casting/Recast)
Objective:
No this isn’t about a tuna melt, though looking at this sandwich makes me hungry. Rather this about the melt function and others in the Reshape package.
If you’re like me you have to go look up the documentation each time a reshape is needed for data. I want to get ahead of the curve and practice. I found a great website with some exercises written by John Akwei - it can be found @ https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick EA on Messier and Herschel Catalogues</title>
      <link>/post/messier_herschel/messierherschel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/messier_herschel/messierherschel/</guid>
      <description>Quick EA on Messier and Herschel Data Sets
Purpose:
I have had this data set for a while. I was curious to see if there were any patterns within it. While this analysis is exploratory in nature and I didn’t set out to answer a particular question, I did, however, find myself asking questions. Like how did Messier miss all the objects that Herschel had found in Ursa Major (Big Dipper)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytics on Classified Section of Cloudy Nights (5,546 ads)</title>
      <link>/post/cloudy_nights/cloudy_nights_scrape/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cloudy_nights/cloudy_nights_scrape/</guid>
      <description>Introduction:
I wanted to see if there were any trends within the Cloudy Nights Classifieds. I obtained the data using R. I also used R for the analysis.
If you have any questions or concerns you can reach out to me via shockley7772@icloud.com
Histogram of the number of Views per Ad.
ggplot(data, aes(Views_final)) + geom_bar(col = &amp;quot;steelblue&amp;quot;) + labs(title = &amp;quot;Histogram of Views per Classified ad&amp;quot;, subtitle = &amp;quot;Eyepiece Classifieds Only&amp;quot;, x= &amp;quot;Number of Views per Ad&amp;quot;, y = &amp;quot;Frequency&amp;quot;, caption = &amp;quot;Source: Cloudy Nights Classifieds&amp;quot;) + theme_bw() Looks as if most of the classified ads get around 250 looks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Sermon Sentiment Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/easter_sermon/tim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/easter_sermon/tim/</guid>
      <description>Objective:I was curious what a sermon would look like doing text analysis with the Syuzhet Package (https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/syuzhet/vignettes/syuzhet-vignette.html). I chose Pastor Tim Knight’s Easter message. I obatined the mp4 off of the Church website and converted it to text using an application (I didn’t know that could be done). I then uploaded the text into R and began the analysis which can be seen below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eno Double Nest Hammock Review Analysis (Amazon User Reviews)</title>
      <link>/post/eno_hammock/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/eno_hammock/test/</guid>
      <description>IntroductionThis analysis was performed as an experiment to see what can be derived from User Reviews. The questions were as follows:
What is the distribution of Reviews as it relates to star rankings?How do the Number of Reviews compare over time?How do the Number of Reviews compare over time by star ranking and count?What is the average sentiment score using SentimentR package?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jim Comey&#39;s A Higher Loyalty Amazon Review Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/jim_comey/comey_markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/jim_comey/comey_markdown/</guid>
      <description>Findings:It is estimated that 6% of purchasers on Amazon write reviews. If that number is constant than there was a sharp decline in Sales shortly after the publication of Mr. Comey’s Book.
I also found that the Kindle Edition of the book outsold (based on the reviews) Hardcover. It makes sense since Kindle Books are cheaper and faster to receive.
The Bigram Word Cloud turned out well and is informative.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Red Wine Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/red_wine/wine_report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/red_wine/wine_report/</guid>
      <description>Objective: My objective was to see if I could predict whether a wine was good or bad using the Random Forest Algorithm (using Random Forest and FFTrees). To run the model I train it on 70% of the data. I then test it against the test set or the other 30% to see how it does. Before I start the random Forest I do some Exploratory Analysis to see those factors that contribute to a wine being classified a Good Wine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>My email address is chris.shockley@gmail.com. My github repository can be found at https://github.com/astronomerforfun.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>