<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>K Means on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/k-means/</link>
    <description>Recent content in K Means on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/k-means/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Can the k means algorithm correctly identify a flower by its petal length and width alone?</title>
      <link>/post/kmeans/kmeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kmeans/kmeans/</guid>
      <description>K Means ClusteringK Means Clustering is awesome. It’s what’s called unsupervised learning where there is no prediction variable. The algorithm attemps to cluster data based on its similarity. So in this case I’m going to feed the algorithm the petal width and petal length of three sets of flowers and see whether or not can appropriately group the data.
To implement k means we have to specify the number of clusters we want the data to be grouped into.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What?  Hypertune Using glmnet and Caret by Max Kuhn?  Yep.  Pass it along.</title>
      <link>/post/glmnet/glmnet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/glmnet/glmnet/</guid>
      <description>glmnet package
Objective:So in this blog I am going to go through a lesson I recently took with a gentlemen by the name Bharatendra Rai, where he goes through the glmnet model in detail.
The reason this model is great is that you can hypretune it, which you will see momentarily. It is an equal to the Random Forests but where glmnet takes the lead is with the amount of information you can pull from the model and its parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>