<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>K Means on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/k-means/</link>
    <description>Recent content in K Means on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/k-means/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>If you&#39;re considering learning R start with Dplyr and work your way from there!</title>
      <link>/post/dplyr/test/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/dplyr/test/</guid>
      <description>Objective:I wanted to give a quick once over of dplyr in less than 10 minutes. This is an intro that will get you started. After watching the video pull down the Cheat sheet off of R Studio’s Website and study it. Practice for two weeks and if you like what you see give it another week and then move full time into R for analytics. If you’re not into it its ok too as there are other languages, like Python, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can the k means algorithm correctly identify a flower by its petal length and width alone?</title>
      <link>/post/kmeans/kmeans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/kmeans/kmeans/</guid>
      <description>K Means ClusteringK Means Clustering is awesome. It’s what’s called unsupervised learning where there is no prediction variable. The algorithm attemps to cluster data based on its similarity. So in this case I’m going to feed the algorithm the petal width and petal length of three sets of flowers and see whether or not can appropriately group the data.
To implement k means we have to specify the number of clusters we want the data to be grouped into.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>