<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tensorflow on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/tensorflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tensorflow on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tensorflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it an Airplane or Automobile? Neural Network using Keras and Randomly Dowloaded Images from the Internet</title>
      <link>/post/images/script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/images/script/</guid>
      <description>Image ClassificationObjective: I wanted to see if I could build a Neural Network that could identify a Plane vs a Car. To do so I downloaded 12 pictures, 6 of which were airplanes and 6 that were cars. I then created the Network using Google Tensorflow and Keras Package to train the model. I then tested the model on two pictures. The results are below:
Methodology:
Download Pictures using ReadImagesNormalize Pictures since they are different sizesReshape Pictures for Model using array_reshape from Keras PackageCreate Training Set and Training Labels/Create Test Set and LabelsBuild Neural NetworkRun the ModelTest model on never before seen pictures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google -- Thank you for giving us Tensorflow and Keras...</title>
      <link>/post/keras_ctg/script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/keras_ctg/script/</guid>
      <description>First what is Deep Learning?Deep Learning. Uhhh… Hmmmm… Well… I know how to implement some of these deep(er) learning algorithms/models, but I’m just now getting my brain around how they work. So I’m coming clean (and I feel so much lighter). My thinking is if I test my model on new data (data the model hasn’t seen) many times over and get good results (that are measurable and repeatable) no need to be concerned with how the thing works under the hood?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>