<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Easier Way to Communicate on Projects (good bye email)</title>
      <link>/post/slack/slackblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/slack/slackblog/</guid>
      <description>What is Slack?Slack is to project communication what dropbox is to sharing documents. A formal definition is a web based software that serves as a communication hub or those invited.
These guys got it right too. I recently started a consulting gig where I was introduced to the app. I found that the CEO on down to the developers were incredibly active – in fact they didn’t use email they just used the message board to communicate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ROC Curve - Is it a Mine or a Rock? - Pick your Sensitivity</title>
      <link>/post/roc/roc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/roc/roc/</guid>
      <description>The Famous ROC CurveROC stands for Receiver Operating Characteristic. Its origin is from sonar back in the 40’s, where it was used to identify submarines. The ROC curve was an important metric in WWII and continues to be today.
Today the ROC curve is used in predictive modelling to distinguish between true positives and true negatives. But if you’re like me you need to see it in action to really understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many sunny days are followed by cloudy days in Seattle on any given year?</title>
      <link>/post/weather_post/mkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/weather_post/mkdown/</guid>
      <description>Seattle Sunny Day StreaksObjective: If you’re like me when the sun comes out after a couple cloudy days my mood lifts quite a bit - even more so than when it’s been sunny for a couple days. Perhaps its the contrast between the two? Nevertheless I was curious how many shifts on average we will have from cloudy days to sunny days, in other words how many mood lifts can we estimate to have in a year living in Seattle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer is Leaving Town</title>
      <link>/post/summer_leaving/summer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/summer_leaving/summer/</guid>
      <description>I’ve never been good with saying good-bye. But that’s exactly what I find myself doing. Waving good bye to Summer and its caravans of warm sunny days, clear lakes and long evenings trail behind. And even if the curtain comes back up in September and Summer plays a finale – I know – the show – is coming to an end. It just sucks!
Over the past few months I have had the best time – from my first overnight hike (in the dark) at Ancient Lakes to climbing 4,000 ft with my Niece at Crystal Mountain inside Mount Rainier National Park.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>