<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorial on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</title>
    <link>/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorial on Chris&#39;s Data Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorial on Web Scraping (Basic) - Wiki Tables</title>
      <link>/post/website/rvest_tables_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/website/rvest_tables_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Web Scraping Tutorial (Wiki Tables)One of my favorite things to do is to scrape web data for analysis in R. Below you will find a simple example where we will scrape a list of Messier Objects from Wiki.
Workflow for Scraping Wiki TablesRead in page needed to scrape;Scrape the Table using Rvest (Wiki Tables do not need the Node function);Convert to Data Frame;Clean up Data;Analyze.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Regex or to Not?</title>
      <link>/post/regex/untitled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/regex/untitled/</guid>
      <description>Is Regex Necessary?Yep. If you’re new to programming or R. Learn Regex. It will help you so much when your data asks of you to do data-gymnastics. Below you will find the steps I took to start learning Regex.
Online Tutorialhttp://www.regexone.com
This is a great site to get your feet wet. You can do it in an hour and when you’re done you’ll have a working knowledge of Regex and be able to do the most common Regex tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Melt and Cast When You Can Recast?</title>
      <link>/post/melt/melt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/melt/melt/</guid>
      <description>Reshape Data Practice (Melt/Casting/Recast)
Objective:
No this isn’t about a tuna melt, though looking at this sandwich makes me hungry. Rather this about the melt function and others in the Reshape package.
If you’re like me you have to go look up the documentation each time a reshape is needed for data. I want to get ahead of the curve and practice. I found a great website with some exercises written by John Akwei - it can be found @ https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>